hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says what's the area of the semicircle
inside this equilateral triangle so
we're given an equilateral triangle a
circle with area six and a semicircle
right here this is day 12 of our Advent
calendar for the month of December we're
going to solve 31 Kina ad puzzles in 31
days and if you want to try this one on
your own pause it right now because I'm
going to solve it in one two three first
thing we're given a six and a question
mark I think we should figure out
formulas for both of those the six is
the area of this smaller Circle and the
question mark is the area of this
semicircle let's label the radius of the
smaller Circle little r and the radius
of the bigger semicircle Big R so 6
would be equal to PI Little R 2 and the
question mark is going to be equal to Pi
big r^ 2 / 2 these look important let's
put boxes around them and our goal is to
find this question mark I think we need
to find some relationship with the Big R
and the little r and then we should be
able to do some substitution from here
let's drop this perpendicular bis sector
and let's make this black and white
first I want to focus on this orange
triangle let's zoom in right here this
line bisected an equilateral triangle so
this is normally 60° up here but this
angle will be half of that or 30° and
then this angle right here is built off
of the radius and the tangent line the
radius of any Circle will meet its
tangent line at 90° and then all three
of these angles add up to 180 so this
one would be 60°
our orange triangle is a 306090 triangle
that is a special right triangle and
it's always true that the hypotenuse is
twice as long as the shortest side so
this distance right here will be two
little r and that correlates to this
right up here this piece is a radius of
the small circle we'll call that little
r and since the whole thing is too
little r this remaining piece will also
be little r and then while we're ated
this piece right here is also a radius
let's call it little r and we can finish
this this is a radius of the semicircle
so let's call this Big R so the entire
height of our equilateral triangle is
Big R + 3 little r next let's focus on
this larger triangle and let's zoom in
on it it will also be 30° up here and
for the same reason this angle will also
be 90 de and the remaining angle will be
60 so this is another 30 6090 where the
hypotenuse is twice the length of the
smaller side so this distance will be 2
Big R so this whole distance is 2 Big R
this is one Big R R which leaves one
more Big R right here and this is the
relationship we wanted we have Big R is
the same thing as three little r this
looks important let's put an irregular
octagon around it and now we're ready
for our original equations down here in
the place of the Big R we can plug in
three little r and this exponent will
distribute to both of these to give us
3^2 little r^ 2 3^2 is equal to 9 and
now let's rearrange this a little so we
have the question mark is equal to 9 pi
little r^ 2 / 2 well Pi little r s is
equal to 6 so in the place of this we
can plug in 6 and then 9 * 6 is 54 and
54 / 2 is 27 let's give it a label of
units squared and that is the answer to
our question the area of this semicircle
is 27 unit squared how exciting this is
our answer for day 12 and this is the
puzzle for day 13 we're given the areas
of these two triangles and it wants to
know what's the area of the entire
semicircle this looks like it'll be a
fun one how exciting in